Jose Clavel

Full Stack Developer | React, Django Specialist

PROFILE SUMMARY

I am a multilingual software developer with seven years of formal and informal experience, focusing on full-stack web application programming across multiple frameworks and architectures. I have a strong background in full-stack application development, including JavaScript, React, Next.js, Node.js, Vue, Python, and Django.

My professional journey is defined by leading complex technology projects and consistently delivering high-quality solutions across multiple platforms. I combine technical proficiency, strategic vision, and a commitment to continuous learning to ensure that every project I undertake meets and exceeds expectations.

SKILLS

Core Skills: Software Development, Full-stack development, Back-end Development, Front-end Development, Software Development Lifecycle (SDLC), RESTful APIs, Microservices, Agile/Scrum, TDD, CI/CD, API Integration, Data Analysis, Data Management, Error Reduction, Process Optimization, Business Requirements Analysis, Scalable Solutions, Technical Specifications, Custom Solutions.

Programming Languages: Python, PHP, JavaScript, Typescript, Java, C#, SQL.

Front-End Technologies: React, Next.js, Vue.js, jQuery, AngularJS

Back-End Technologies: NodeJS, Express, Flask, Python, Django, Laravel, CodeIgniter, Spring Boot

E-commerce Platforms: Shopify, WordPress, WooCommerce **Databases Management:** MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB **Platforms:** AWS, Azure, DevOps Practices, Docker, Git

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full-Stack Engineer

Advertise Purple Inc, UK

March 2022 - February 2024

- Helped build a portal that allows users to see and control the impact of the advertising product on their business.
- Used Jira and worked harmoniously with the team to deliver the project on time.
- Maintained consistency and stability of the existing app throughout the engagement by employing a testdriven approach.

Technical Team Lead

Vodafone UK, UK

March 2019 - February 2022

- Developed a new portal for business customers that allowed easier marketing for products and services.
- Collaborated within a multidisciplinary team with high efficiency.
- Delivered a highly successful project, granting the client a competitive edge over their competitors.
- Spotted deficiencies with a locally built tool and pushed back against using it in our team. The tool soon after was abandoned, saving our team a lot of time by avoiding it.

Senior Full-Stack Developer

VoCoVo, UK

February 2018 – February 2019

• Developed an app that allowed supermarket staff across the UK to talk with their colleagues via a push-to-talk headset wirelessly.

- Delivered high-quality functional software with reporting capabilities, allowing the client to advertise the efficiency of their product, further increasing the startup's success.
- Launched the project, allowing the startup client to hit Deloitte Tech Fast 50, a list of fastest-growing companies in the UK.

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Developer Associate

- Demonstrated proficiency in developing and deploying applications on the AWS platform, including services such as EC2, S3, Lambda, DynamoDB, and API Gateway.
- Acquired skills in leveraging AWS SDKs to integrate applications with AWS services, optimizing performance and scalability for cloud-based solutions.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Science in Computer Science | University Santo Tomas

SOFT SKILLS

Team Leadership, Cross-functional Collaboration, Communication, Mentoring & Coaching, Problem Solving, Risk Management Troubleshooting, Code Review, Conflict Resolution, Task Prioritization, Decision-Making.